[Music]
hi everyone welcome back to the channel
this week's video is cherry garcia now
this is the second time i've made this
the first time
all the files on the camera became
corrupt so i had to remake it
did learn a little bit about making this
from the first one
so what you're going to see now is the
final product
so stick with us and i'll show you how
to make it
so the first thing we're going to do
here is make a really
concentrated cherry syrup it's almost
like a jam
but with less sugar and less pectin
so we've taken our cherries and removed
the stalks put them in a pan and heated
with a little bit of water
a little bit of sugar and brought them
up to temperature a good rolling boil
for about five or ten minutes to soften
the cherries down and get that juice out
then separate the cherry flesh so you
left
just syrup and put that back on the hob
and heat it up for 5-10 minutes again
and a good
rolling boil at that point you can add a
bit of pectin if you want
to allow a little bit more coagulation
to happen
when that's ready decant that into a
small container
ready to use later so in the first video
that you
haven't actually seen i actually took
the same cherries and soaked them in a
sugar syrup it was
really heavy one-to-one sugar syrup
soaked them in that
overnight to try and absorb that sugar
syrup into the cherries
so they wouldn't freeze like little
bricks that didn't work
so what we've done this time is taken
some of
opi's black cherries which are soaked in
luxado kirsch
we're going to prepare the base now put
your milk and sugar in a pan and
get that sugar dissolved and this is the
point where you're gonna add your cherry
syrup
cherry garcia is a cherry flavored ice
cream so you need that
really strong cherry syrup to add the
flavor and that color to it as well
now cherry garcia in the stores i
haven't had it for ages
it was really really mild in flavor so
we're going to punch it with a lot of
cherry flavor here
once you've got your ice cream base
ready add in your milk powder and then
add your cherry syrup
get it to the color you need and decant
it into a container it's at this point
in this recipe that i added the cream
it really cools it down quickly so you
can put it straight in the fridge
without worrying about temperatures
after your base is chilled completely in
the fridge could take two to four hours
depending on where you are and what
fridge you got
you're gonna load it up and churn away
again 15 to 30 minutes depending on the
machine you use
once that's completely churned now
you're going to add in the other parts
so this is where we're going to add in
those chopped opie's black cherries
and in this version we're going to add
the chopped chocolate
now in the u.s it's one thing and in the
uk it's something else
one recipe has chocolate one recipe has
fudge i don't know why it's different
but we're gonna go with chocolate this
time
[Music]
layer it in as you would do normally get
your container closed up and put it in
the freezer for a few hours
[Music]
do
so the ice cream's been in the freezer
for days now at this point because it's
wednesday and i made it on
saturday or whatever it was so we're
gonna get it out get scooping
[Music]
there we go really nice colors like a
soft pink
it's actually it's a little bit more
pink than the ben jerry's one sometimes
you open up or you used to open up the
tub and it was
basically white but let's
see what this tastes like with the
opie's cherries
and the chocolate bits in there as well
[Music]
really nice soft cherry flavor going
through the ice cream
that's actually quite important because
the ben jerry's one doesn't have a lot
of flavor
so you need to make sure that you make a
real strong
cherry compote if you will to boost the
cherry flavor
into your base otherwise you're going to
really struggle not all cherries are
created equally
over here in the uk we get unknown
types of cherries from god knows where a
bit flavourless to be honest so i really
really had to boil that down to get that
flavor punch from it
i know ben and jerry's used to use bing
cherries originally
we can't get those i've never seen them
but
i don't know what they do to them either
because they never used to freeze
hard and the first time i made this the
unknown cherries
did freeze solid these ones
are not as bad but
if you want to make this just go and buy
luxado cherries
they freeze perfectly they bite really
well
no iciness luxado cherries all the way
like i said before there's two different
variations of this
the us and the uk version why they're
different i don't know
one has chocolate fudge flex throughout
one has
chocolate flecks throughout different
things
probably just a wording issue maybe that
because ben jerry's adds water to their
chocolate to create a softer consistency
they probably can't call it chocolate so
maybe it's the same thing but
who knows but this is a really it's a
it's a classic everyone wants to know
how to make
cherry garcia i'm a big cherry fan and i
was always disappointed with the lack of
flavor but here you've got whatever
flavor you put into it
so go to town choose the best cherries
you can find
if you're using fresh cherries soak them
in something for a good few days before
you put them in here
otherwise you'll end up with little
cherry bullets with no flavor at all
all in all this was an absolute success
second time around
first time around not so much but hey
we've got to learn somewhere aren't we
anyway i hope you enjoyed this video
cherry garcia ben and jerry's
thanks very much for watching don't
forget to like and subscribe and we'll
see you next week
you